Finding Aid for John C. Dancy papers, 1920-1960
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John C. Dancy papers 1920-1960
Dancy, John C. (John Campbell), 1888-1968.
1 linear foot and 1 oversize volume
85120 Aa 2; AC
Executive director of the Detroit Urban League. Correspondence, scrapbook, photographs, and miscellanea concerning personal matters, the work of the Urban League, and the concerns of the black community of Detroit.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The papers came as part of the records received from the Detroit Urban League (donor no. 4042 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
John C. Dancy was executive director of the Detroit Urban League, serving from 1918 until his retirement in 1960. Educated at Phillips Exeter Academy in New Hampshire and the University of Pennsylvania, Dancy came to Detroit and to the Urban League in 1918. One of his continuing goals as executive director was to find jobs for African Americans both in the automobile industry and in Detroit's commercial and retail establishments. In addition, Dancy involved himself in the community in other ways, as a member of the Detroit House of Correction Commission, as secretary-treasurer of Parkside Hospital, as a member of the Metropolitan Area Planning Commission, and as recording secretary of the Detroit Council of Churches.
The collection consists of personal correspondence, a scrapbook documenting in part his career as executive director of the Detroit Urban League, and scattered photographs. There is also the transcript of an oral history interview of John Dancy made in 1964.
Subjects:
Detroit Urban League.; African Americans--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
African Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; Banquets.; Dancy, John C. (John Campbell), 1888-1968.; Dancy, Malinda W.; Detroit (Mich.); Dwellings.; Horace H. Rackham Educational Memorial (Detroit, Mich.); Mess halls.; Musicians.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Personal and biographical material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    (include transcript of oral history interview conducted by Marvin Petroelje, April 10, 1964)
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1928-1936 (Box 1)
  - 1937 (Box 1)
  - 1938 (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942 (Box 1)
  - 1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944 (Box 1)
  - 1945 (Box 1)
  - 1946 (Box 1)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
  - 1948 (Box 1)
  - 1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950 (Box 1)
  - 1951 (Box 1)
  - 1952-1955 (Box 1)
  - 1956-1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - National Urban League materials (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Loose items from scrapbook, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Dancy, his wife, and associates and friends; also photograph of the Horace H. Rackham Educational Building, Detroit, Michigan (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1920-1947 (Volume 1)
    (The scrapbook largely concerns the work of John Dancy as covered in the Detroit press (including African American newspapers)
Related Material
The library also has an extensive collection of the records of the Detroit Urban League during the period when Dancy was executive director.